I guess one thing I I am the rest of the
我想一件事II上午 的休息
staff request is that you whenever you
工作人员的要求是， 你 只要你
have a question you first read the book
有你第一次读这本书的一个问题
and then you reread the assignment and
然后 你重读 分配 和
you maybe reread it again and then you
你也许再 然后 你 再读一遍
ask us because a lot of the questions
问我们，因为有很多 的问题，
we're getting are ones where we just say
我们得到的是那些在这里我们只说
look at this page of the book look at
看这页书看的
this paragraph of the assignment look at
本款分配的样子在
this part of the file that you were
你是该文件 的这一部分
given and so I mean there's a lot of
给予所以我的意思是有很多的
stuff and I understand how sometimes
的东西，我了解有时
it's easy to miss things so not saying
它很容易错过事情，所以不是说
don't ever ask questions but just before
永远不要问的问题，但 之前
you ask your questions trying to figure
你问你的问题，试图弄清楚
out if I really should have come through
我是否 真的应该 来过
the resources I have available to see if
我可以看到，如果资源
the answer to my question is can be
回答我的 问题是 可
found there so anyways enjoy the web so
发现有这么反正享受网络进行，因此
today is a sort of second part of a
今天是一个排序的第二部分
two-part lecture on integers and integer
在整数和整数两部分讲座
arithmetic last time we looked at
算术最后一次 看
representations about how bit patterns
有关如何位模式表示
can be interpreted as either unsigned
可被解释为任一无符号的
numbers meaning they range between zero
数字意味着它们的范围 0 之间
and two to the word size minus one or as
和两 字的大小减去一个或
two's complement numbers which is the
二补数这是
most compliment you away to represent
最恭维你而去代表
what are sometimes called signed numbers
什么有时 被称为 符号数
ones it can be their negative or
者也可以是 他们的 消极或
positive and by the way there are other
积极 的方式还有 其他
ways to represent signed numbers out
的方式来表示有符号数出
there but tooth complemented so so
有，但牙齿的补充等等等等
overwhelmingly the most used system that
绝大多数最常用的系统，
that's what we concentrate on today what
这就是我们专注于什么今天
we'll do is now go beyond the
我们要做的是 现在超越
representations of these values to talk
这些值的表示说话
about arithmetic operations on them and
在他们关于算术运算和
some of their properties and what we'll
它们的一些性质，以及我们将
do in general we talk about the unsigned
做一般 我们谈论 的无符号
case which is in some ways easier to
情况下这是在某些方面更容易
understand and more intuitive and then
了解更直观 ，然后
talk about the two's complement case so
说说补这样的情况下
the basic rule on this is if you take
在这个基本的规则是，如果你拿
two numbers that range between up to the
两个数字达之间的范围
maximum value of an unsigned number
一个无符号数的 最大值
add them but in principle you might need
加上他们，但 在原则上 ，你可能需要
to get an extra bit to represent that
以获得额外的比特来表示
thumb if you want to represent the true
如果你想代表真正的拇指
some sort of integer sum of those two
某种这两个整数总和
numbers
数字
because you're doubling it and
因为你加倍并
unfortunately we can't just go out and
不幸的是，我们不能 只是出去
add more bits to your computer
更多位添加到您的计算机
indefinitely so we just stop it at some
无限期所以我们只是 阻止它的一些
point and say well whatever bit happened
点 ，说什么也 发生了 一点
to be in that sort of next / bit
要在那种未来/位
position we're just going to drop it and
位置，我们只是要删除它 和
pretend it doesn't exist and say that
假装它不存在，并说，
the result of addition is just whatever
另外的结果就是什么
the W bit pattern you get if you only
W位模式你，如果你只
consider the first W bits out of it with
考虑第1W位出它与
no warning no messages no error or
无警告没有消息 没有错误或
anything this is just it happens
什么这 只是它发生
silently so for at each compliment this
这样默默地在每个恭维这
is not such a hard thing to understand
是不是这样一个困难的事情理解
it can be thought of as just modular
它可以被看作 只是模块化 的
arithmetic computing modulo the two to
算术运算模的两
the word size and so I'm going to use
字的大小，所以我打算 使用
some examples and this time I've got
一些例子， 这一次我有
them worked out a little more carefully
他们多一点经过深思熟虑
so I will get mixed up as much and we'll
所以我会弄混尽可能多的和我们
use the word size of four here and as I
用四个词大小在这里和我
mentioned last time it really helps with
上次提到的它确实有帮助
this to work do the examples with small
这个工作做小例子
word sizes to get a your intuition for
字长得到了你的直觉
it rather than trying to write out
而不是尝试写出来
32-bit numbers or 64-bit numbers or
32位数字或64位数字或
something like that so if you think
类似的东西，所以，如果你认为
about in the unsigned case a 4-bit
关于在无符号的情况下 的4位
number means that it will range between
数意味着它将之间的范围内
0 and 2 to the 4th minus 1 or 15 right
0 和2至第四减1或15右
and so let's just do a few examples of
所以，让我们只是 做了几个 例子
cases where it overflows so if you add
它溢出，所以如果你添加的情况下
13 to 5
13〜5
first of all you know I assume already
首先你知道，我认为已经
that you just add binary numbers the way
你只需添加二进制数的方式
you learned in school of just doing
你 的只是在做 学校里学到的
carries and so forth except it's all
携带等等，除了它的所有
modulo two so this is zero carry one one
模2 所以这是零携带一个一个
zero carry one zero carry one
零携带一个零携带一个
so in principle to represent the sum
所以在原则上表示总和
which is this is five so to represent 18
这是这是5，以便以代表18
you need five bits not four but we're
你需要五个比特不是四个 ，但我们
just going to conveniently drop that
只是要方便丢弃
number and say that this is actually 2
数说，这 其实 是 2
which of course is what 18 module 16 is
这当然就是18模块16
so the unsigned case is really pretty
所以无符号的情况是真的很漂亮
straightforward and we can visualize
简单， 我们可以想像
this in this pictures in the book too by
这在该图片的书 太受
saying if you are representing on the X
他说，如果你 在X代表
and y axis what they call U and V are
和y轴他们所谓的 U和V是
values between 0 and 15 the range of
0 和15之间的范围内的值
possible unsigned numbers and if we're
可能的无符号数，如果我们
going to add those we could get a sum
要添加这些，我们可以得到一个总和
that up to as much as 30 which would in
多达高达 30会在
principle require 5 bits to represent
原则需要5个比特来表示
but what we'll do is we'll just by
但我们要做的是，我们将仅仅通过
dropping that most significant bit what
下降，大多数显著位什么
we do is to create a clip that when you
我们做的是创造一个 夹子 ，当你
roll over from 15 to 16 instead it drops
从15至16，而不是它滴翻转
all the way down to 0 and that's
一路下跌到0，这就是
referred to as an overflow and then from
被称为溢出，然后从
there we'll build up to the maximum
这样，我们就建立了最大
value here will be 14 which is 30 minus
这里的值 将是14这是30个负
16 so what we've done is basically as
16 所以我们所做的基本上 为
this picture shows when we overflow we
这个图片显示，当我们 溢出我们
effectively subtract off 2 to the W from
有效地减去关2至从 W
the sum and keep it within the
总和，并保持它的内
representable range of W bit numbers so
W位数字表示的范围，
that's untimed two's complement once the
这是不计时的 补一次
first thing I want to convince you of is
我想说服你第一件事 是
that two's complement addition
两个补码加法
looks just like a regular edition in
看起来就像一个普通 版的
other words I can perform a subtraction
换句话说，我可以执行减法
and addition of subtraction of numbers
和另外数的减法
by using this tooth compliment
通过使用这种牙齿恭维
representation for negative numbers so
表现为负数，以便
well let me just show you some examples
还有让我告诉你一些 例子
of that so first of all remember that
那所以首先 请记住 ，
what range of values what's the smallest
什么范围的值有什么最小
number that could be represented with a
可 与一个 来表示数
four bit the most negative number four
四位最负排名第四
bit two's complement number minus eight
位二进制补码数零下八
and the largest plus seven thank you so
而最大的加七太感谢你
let's just do some examples if we took
我们只是做了一些例子，如果我们把
this number 1 1 0 1 as the two's
这个数字1 1 0 1为二的
complement number is minus 3 and we add
补数为零下3， 我们添加
it to 5 we'll get what we got before
它5，我们会得到什么，我们之前得到
and we're not good at we're going to
我们不善于我们要
ignore whatever carry bid it is and so
忽略任何 随身携带的出价是等
the result is - I'm going behold that's
结果是-我 要看见 那
what five minus three is so it seems
什么五减三 是看起来是这样的
like magic because it is Tuesday and
像变魔术一样 ，因为它是周二和
that's why part of the reason why I
这就是为什么部分为什么我
choose complement is to the most
选择的补充是 最
commonly used way of representing signed
代表签署了常用的方法
numbers because the same hardware the
数字，因为同一个硬件平台
same algorithms that are used for doing
被用来做相同的算法
addition in work for either unsigned or
除了在工作无符号或
two's complement numbers and this works
二补数和这个作品
as well just to show you if the overflow
如干脆如果溢出给你看
goes if the resulting film is goes the
去如果所得到的膜是那张
other way so if I have minus 3 and minus
所以其他的方式，如果我有零下3号和减号
5 and plus 3 and I add those together
5加3， 我添加这些在一起
I'll get 1 1 1 0 which is minus 2 so
我会得到1 1 1 0，这是零下2 SO
again if you use the same patterns for
如果您再次使用相同的模式
the same rule for addition as you do
对于除了为你做同样的规则
with an unsigned case you'll get two
用一个无符号的情况下，你会得到两个
complementary rhythm so let's look at a
互补 节奏让 我们来看 一个
few cases where the two's complement
少数情况下，补码
overflows so if we take 3
溢出，所以如果我们采取3
and -6 and we add them together we'll
和-6，我们把它们加起来，我们将
get one one one zero we're going to drop
得到一个一个一个零 ， 我们要 降
off the carry which is what seven so
关闭这就是7所以进
we've added two negative numbers and
我们已经添加了两个负数和
it's become positive
它已经成为积极的
and that's referred to as a negative
而这被称为 负
overflow and the reason of course is the
溢出， 当然原因是
number minus nine can't be represented
数量减去9不能代表
in a 4-bit to compliment number so it
在一4位补码 ，因此
overflowed you'll notice that the cost
你溢的会发现成本
seven of course differs from minus 9 by
当然7 由 从负9的不同之
16 and that's not next to and then going
16这不是旁边，然后去
the other direction if we had two large
另一方向，如果我们有两个大
positive numbers so if we add 7 & 5
正数，所以如果我们增加7和5
we'll get minus six so this was seven
我们会减去六所以这是七
plus five is minus four and so this is
加五 等于减 四所以这是
referred to as positive overflow we've
提到我们已经为正溢出
taken two positive numbers and added
采取了两个正数并添加
them together and gotten a negative
他们在一起，并得到一个 负
result and you could see this by the way
结果，你可以顺便看到这个
if you think about this addition we took
如果你 认为这个 此外，我们采取了
seven and five would be twelve and this
七其中5位为十二，这
is the bit level representation of
是的位级表示
twelve it's just that because this is
12 这只是因为这 是
not the time bit we think of that as
没有时间位我们认为， 随着
minus four not positive twelve and so
减四不积极十二年等等
that's the the idea of two's complement
这是两个互补的想法
overflow and you can see there's two
溢出，你可以看到有两家
different cases here one is where the
这里不同的情况 之一是当
number that the sum was if we looked at
数量总和是，如果我们看
the true sum the numbers that you'd get
真正的总和数字，你会得到
for example 12 is too big to represent
例如12 太大代表
and so when we think of that as a two's
所以，当我们认为 ，作为一个二进制
complement number it becomes now a
补数现在变成一个
negative number
负数
so that's positive overflow similarly if
所以这是积极的溢出同样，如果
we have two negative numbers and we add
我们 有两个负数 和我们添加
them together so that the sum is too
他们在一起，使 之和过
small to negative to represent then
小到负来表示则
those become positive numbers that's
那些成为正数这
negative overflow and you can see that
负溢出，你可以看到，
in this picture the same ideas before
在这张照片 同样的想法之前
except there's three regions this is and
除了有三个区域，这是和
by the way now you'll see our numbers
顺便说一下，现在你会看到我们的数字
range between minus 8 and positive 7 and
零下8 和正 7 和之间范围
the sum to come will also range between
总和来 还会之间的范围
minus 8 and a positive 7 but there's
零下8 和积极的 7，但有
these three regions one is the where
这三个区域之一 是哪里
everything's fine
一切都 很好
it's within the representable range the
它是表示的范围内，
other is where the sum was so far toward
另一种是其中总和是迄今为止向
the negative side that it becomes
它成为 负侧
positive or where it's so high on the
正面或者它是在如此之高
positive side that it becomes negative
它变为负值积极的一面
and so part of data web you'll you'll
等 数据网络的 一部分 ，你会，你会
learn to understand these quite in quite
学会在相当相当了解这些
precisely but that lets the idea it's a
但恰恰让这个想法这是一个
little bit counterintuitive to say you
有点违反直觉说你
know somehow I can accept the idea the
知道不知何故， 我可以接受的想法
modular arithmetic for unsigned numbers
模运算的无符号数
there's some sort of mathematical beauty
有某种数学之美
to a modular arithmetic and this disk
以模块化算术和该 磁盘
looks like kind of useless right from a
看起来像是那种 从 无用 权
from a operational characteristic but
从一个操作特性，但
it's the way it is and we're stuck with
这是事情是这样的，我们不得不接受
it
它
and multiplication is basically the same
和乘法基本上是相同的
idea in fact all the operations are
想法其实 所有的操作都
basically the same idea that if you
基本上是相同的 想法， 如果你
can't represent it within the word size
字长内不能代表它
you just take the lower W bits so all
你只需要较低的写位，因此所有
this complicated notation here is just a
这里这个复杂的符号仅仅是一个
way of saying in principle if you take
原则上说，如果你 采取的方式
2w bit numbers and multiply them
2瓦特位数字和它们相乘
together you may need a the result may
同时 你可能需要一个结果可能
require as much as 2 times W bits to
需要多达2倍数W位
represent before addition its W plus 1
除 以其w加 1 日前代表
multiplication you actually have to
乘法你确实有
double because you're potentially
双因为你可能
squaring the largest number and so again
现蕾数量最多，因此再次
we don't want to just keep doubling our
我们不希望只保留数量增加了一倍
word size over and over again we'll run
字长一遍又一遍，我们会运行
out of bits very quickly that way and so
出位的很快呀等等
we just truncate it at W bits and for
我们只截断它为W 位和
the unsigned case it's again modular
未签名的情况下， 它的模块化再次
arithmetic it's something that you can
算术它的东西，你可以
kind of understand and believe but for
一种理解和相信但
two and so again let's just do a few
二等再次让我们只是做了一些
examples and I won't try and
例子， 我不会尝试
work out multiplying in binary is like
制定乘以二进制 像
multiplying in decimal you do a big
在小数乘以你做一个大
table and it takes a long time so I
表中， 并需要很长的 时间，所以我
won't try to do that but let me just
不会尝试这样做， 但我只想
show a few examples so if I multiply
展示一些例子，所以如果我乘
three times five is of course equal to
三次五是 当然等于
15 and in an unsigned number I can
15和一个无符号数我可以
represent that right so that's okay but
代表权所以这是 好的，但
if I multiply a five times five then
如果我乘五个乘五则
that would have representation if I were
这将有代表性，如果我是
to think about it as possibly as many as
作为可能想想 多达
eight bits it would have a
八位那就有
representation with an extra bit and I'm
一个额外的位，我表示
going to throw this part away and so I'd
要扔这部分路程 ，所以我最好
call that nine which of course is equal
叫那九这当然是 相等
to 25 960
25 960
um and and so that's the general idea of
UM和等那的总体思路
it is regardless of whatever is in this
它是 不管的无论是在这
upper part of the work of the product
该产品的工作上部
I'm just going to discard that and only
我只是要 丢弃 ， 只
look at the lower one and vice gets a
看看下一个副 得到了
little more interesting with the two's
更 有趣一点与两个的
complement case so let's look at what
补充的情况下让我们看看什么
that does and the answer is even a
，做答案是连
little bit stranger that you not only
有点陌生 ，你不仅
trunk throw away whatever high order
树干扔掉任何高阶
bits happen to be there but whatever bit
位恰好是有，但无论位
gets left in this position will
在这个位置上离开被将
determine whether it's a positive or a
确定它是否是一个积极或
negative result even though with
阴性结果即使与
completely irrespective of the signs of
完全不考虑的迹象
the original two operands so that can
原来两个操作数，这样就可以
make you go all over the place
让你去所有 的 地方
so if we had five times four or 20 that
所以，如果我们有五次四 ，20
would be represented in this 8-bit form
将在这8位形式来表示
like so and we just call that for right
像这样，我们只是调用 右
is we're showing this away but if we did
在我们这个展示遥远，但如果我们这样做
five times five as we saw before that's
五次五象我们看到的前
represented like this
这样表示
and that sum now becomes so we're
这一数额现在变得如此我们
throwing away this and this becomes our
扔掉这一点，这将成为我们的
sign bit so the result is minus 8 plus 1
符号位，因此结果为负8加1
or minus 7 so you see this is a similar
或零下7所以你看，这是一个类似
to an example we showed at the beginning
一个例子，我们表现出在开始
of the first lecture that you can have
第一 讲 的 ， 你 可以有
two positive numbers and multiply them
两个正数 和 它们 相乘
and get a negative result and because of
并获得并且因为阴性结果
the sort of course of this overflow
排序这个溢出 ，当然
question there oh I'm just taking 25 and
问题还有 哦，我 只是把25 和
writing it in binary yeah if you want to
以二进制写它是啊，如果你想
you know you start with the two numbers
你知道你开始使用两个号码
I'm not going to do well actually this
我不打算 其实这个 很好办
one's an easy one there's a trick for
一个是一个容易有一个把戏
this if you want to know multiply a
这一点，如果你想知道一个乘以
number by a power of two we're going to
通过两个动力 ， 我们要数
show that later you just shift it left
结果表明 ， 以后 你刚接班 离开
by two position so that one's an easy
由两个 位置，一个是一个 简单的
one otherwise you have to write out the
一个否则， 你写出来的
table and sum all the results and all
表， 总结所有的结果和所有
that stuff I prefer to what computers do
这些东西我喜欢什么样的电脑做
that
那
and again this to complement stuff one
，这再次补充 一个 东西
interesting feature is that it works for
有趣的特点是，它适用 于
our negative numbers too so if you do
我们负数 过，所以如果你做
this trick of throwing away the
这一招扔掉 的
high-order bit and you'll have overflow
高阶 位，你就会有溢出
cases like before because you're
案件像以前一样，因为你是
throwing away information but the lower
扔掉信息，但较低
bits if the number is representable
如果比特数可表示
you'll get the right result so let me
你会得到正确的结果 ，所以让我
just demonstrate to that to you so this
只是证明给你，让这
is a minus 3 but you remember that this
为负3，但 你记住，这
is equivalent to 13 as an unsigned
是相当于13为一个无符号
number and this is minus 2 which is
数，这是减去2， 其
equivalent to my 14 as an unsigned
相当于我14为一个 无符号
number so now if we multiply 13 times 14
所以现在，如果我们数乘以13倍的14
you get 182 and that has a hex
你会得到182并具有六角
representation of b6
B6的表示
and so just looking at the low order for
所以只盯着低顺序
bit are 0 1 1 0 is 6 and indeed that
位 是0 1 1 0是6 和确实是
negative 3 times minus 2 is 6 so the
负的 3 倍减去2是 6，因此
point being oh and I'm waving my hands
点是哦，我挥舞着我的手
here because I don't want to go through
这里，是因为我不想去通过
all the details but to complement
所有的细节，但补充
multiplication also gives you if you can
乘法也给你，如果你能
do it using the exact same rules and as
做到这一点使用完全相同的规则和
you do for unsigned multiplication the
你无符号乘法做
exact same hardware I should mention
完全相同的硬件，我应该提
that and there are instructions in the
这一点，也有在说明
computer in ways that you can get the
电脑的方式， 你可以得到
upper word of a multiplication too and
乘法的上字 也和
though it's the bit patterns are
虽然它的位模式
different depending on whether it
根据不同的是否
treated as a tooth compliment number
作为齿补码处理
versus unsigned so these typically
与无符号所以这些通常
different instructions for doing that
这样做，不同的指令
computation but 99% of the time or more
但计算的时间或99％ 以上
you just are looking at this lower part
你刚才在看这个下部
of the product and that's the same
该 产品 的 ，这就是同一
whether it's a two's complement or an
无论它是一个二进制补码或
unsigned and it handles negative numbers
无符号，它处理负数
positive but it has these overflow
积极的，但它有这些溢出
characteristics
特点
so as I was talking about there's a
因此，正如我说的 是有一个
trick we can do for multiplying by a
技巧我们可以通过做乘以
power of two which is just to shift the
的 两个电源，其 仅仅是 移位
number to the left and you'll often see
数到左边 ，你会经常看到
that when you have in your code I want
当您 在代码中 有 我想要
to multiply some number by four you'll
四你会乘以一定数目
write in your C code if you look at the
在C代码写的，如果你看一下
assembly code you'll see that what the
汇编代码，你会看到什么
compiler generated is just says oh just
编译器生成只是说：哦，只要
shift it left by two so in general and
移位它留下两所以一般和
you could see why this is true by the
你可以看到为什么这 是真的由
way if you think of the number as the
这样，如果你 想的那样的数
sum of the bits where X sub I is the ice
位的总和，其中X子我是冰
bit and X is the number it represents if
位和X 是代表 如果该号码
I want to if I shift everything left by
我想，如果我转向一切由左
two what I'm effectively doing is
2 什么我切实做好为
increasing their weight by that number
通过这个数字增加自己的体重
of positions so let's just shift by one
位置所以我们只用一个移
if I shift everything to the left by one
如果我通过一个移动的一切向左
which we write like this and see two
我们这样写，并看到两个
left two less symbols so I taking that
左边两个较少的符号，所以我采取这一
sum but now waiting the disk by two to
总和，但现在由两个等待盘
be I plus one by one more and of course
是我加上一个由多一个，当然
that's equal to twice what the original
这等于 原来的 两倍 什么
sum was and so we double the number and
总和为，所以我们双数和
that works although even if you shift
该作品虽然即使你转移
things so that you lose some bits right
事情让你失去了一些正确的位
they they shift off to the left all
他们他们转移到左边 所有
you're doing is the way multiplication
你正在做的是乘法的方式
works
作品
anyhow of truncating to W bit product so
无论如何的截断为W位产品，以便
you'll see this as I mentioned quite
你会看到这是我相当提到
often in in compiled code machine level
经常在编译代码的机器水平
code that they're doing shifts where you
他们正在做的变化，你的代码
might expect them
可能指望他们
to be doing multiplications and the
是做乘法 和
reason for that is an optimization is
原因是 一个优化
historically the multiplication
历史上的乘法
instruction took a lot longer than a
指令采取了很多长于
shift instruction say one clock cycle to
移位指令说， 一个时钟周期
do a shift and it used to be like 11 12
做的移位，并将其用于像 11 12
30 clock cycles to do a multiplication
30个时钟周期来执行一个乘法
nowadays like on the computers we use
如今像 我们使用的计算机
the sharp machines it only take three
锋利的机器 只需要三
clock cycles to do multiplication
时钟周期做乘法
because they added a lot of hardware to
因为他们增加了大量 的硬件来
do that but three clock cycles is still
这样做，但三个时钟周期仍然是
more time than one and so when you can
更多的时间超过一个，所以当你可以
get away with a shift it's generally a
逃脱的转变通常一个是
better idea and the compiler has its own
更好的主意，编译器都有 自己的
kind of judgment calls on when is it
一种判断来电时，它是不是在
more efficient to substitute one
更高效的替代一个
operation for another did we design lose
另一个操作为什么我们 设计输
ground here
这里地面
okay so the idea that if we want to
还好这样的想法 ，如果我们 想
multiply something by 2 to the K we just
乘以2东西去K 我们只是
shift it left by K bit it turns out that
接班留下的千 比特的事实证明 ，
the same almost works for dividing by 2
同样的，几乎 适用于除以2
as well that if you want to divide
还有，如果你想要分割
something by a power of 2 you can shift
由东西2的幂 ，你可以转移
it right by in the same general idea the
它的权利在同一个总体 思路
only thing that becomes a little bit
只有成为 一点点 的事情
quirky is well what if the number you
离奇的是还有什么，如果你的号码
have is not actually divisible by that
已经是不实际整除
power of 2 so for example if we had the
2的幂这样， 例如，如果我们有
number 0 1 what it's going to use yeah
电话号码0 1什么它要使用啊
so that's 6 so if we shift it right by 1
所以这是 6，所以如果我们用 1 右移它
we'll get 0 0 1 0 1 1 thank you which is
我们会得到0 0 1 0 1 1感谢你这是
3 and that's 6 divided by 2 is 3 if we
3， 这就是6除以2是 3，如果我们
shift that again we'll get 1 but of
转变，我们再次将得到 1但
course you know that 3 halves or 1.5 the
当然，你知道，3 两半或1.5
rule on integer division is you round it
整数除法法则是你详谈
down round it towards 0 and so that goes
下一轮它推向0，并让 去
to 1 so this is what the unsigned case
1，因此这是 无符号的情况下，
works fine the sine case which I don't
工作得很好，我不正弦情况
have a slide for
有一个幻灯片
is a little bit less of pretty oh well
是相当少 一 点点哦
first of all you notice if it's a
首先你会注意到，如果它是一个
positive number the shifting rights
正数换档权利
going to be the right thing oh just as
将是正确的事情哦，就像
is for untime but let's take a number
是不定时，但让我们来数
that is negative so this is plus two
这是负的，因此这是加二
minus six right now here's where
减去六 ，现在这里的地方
remember I told you in the previous
记得我告诉过你在前面
lecture there's two ways to do shifting
讲座有两种方法可以做到移
there's logical shifting where you fill
还有就是你填写的逻辑移位
in with zeros and arithmetic shifting
在用零和算术移位
where you fill in with ones and guess
在您填写与那些和猜测
where arithmetic shifting comes in this
其中算术移位来在这
is it when you want to preserve the sign
是不是当你想保留符号
of a number while you're dividing it by
一些当你将其除以
powers of two you want arithmetic shifts
的两个大国想要算术移位
so if we shift this by one we'll keep
所以，如果我们通过一个移动这一点，我们会继续
that sign bit and then copy the other
该符号位，然后复制 其他
ones over all right so we just preserve
那些在 所有的权利 ，所以我们只是保留
this bit here and copied the other ones
这里该位复制其他的人
over and this is minus three and so
过去，这是减三等
that's good but now if we shift again
这是很好的，但现在，如果我们再次转移
arithmetic we will get what
算术我们会得到什么
nice - I can see you guys need to know
不错-我能看到你们需要 知道
how to negate numbers right you don't
如何否定号码的权利 ，你不
know that so I'll show you in a second
知道， 所以我会告诉 你在第二
so here is a little bit problematic that
所以这里是有点问题的 是 ，
we shifted we want to divide by two but
我们转移，我们要除以2，但
the rule should be the same that you
规则应该是 相同的， 你
should round toward zero and what this
要圆趋向于 零，什么这个
is doing is it's rounding toward minus
正在做的是它向负舍入
infinity its rounding
无限的舍入
toward a more negative number than the
朝向比更负的数
truth thing and so there's a little cute
真理的东西，所以有一 点点可爱
little trick that says before you shift
小动作，说你转移前
before you divide by a power of two
之前 除以 二 的幂
before you do the shift you should add a
你 做的转变 之前， 你应该添加
bias which in this case would just be
偏见在这种情况下也只是
one and I'll tell you where that comes
一个，我会告诉你在哪里 自带
from and so if we add those numbers
来自所以如果我们增加这些数字
together we'll get one one one zero
我们一起会得到一个一个一个 零
right and now when we do the shift on
右，现在当我们上移
that we'll get 1 1 1 1 and that's minus
我们会得到1 1 1 1和零下
1 so there's a trick and you'll again
1所以有一个窍门，你再会
you'll see the compiler doing this where
你会看到， 编译器做这个地方
you have in your code divided by 16 and
你已经在你的代码除以16
we'll add a bias and then it will do a
我们将添加一个偏见，然后它会做
right shift instead of calling division
右移，而不是调用师
and by the way division really really is
顺便说一句师真的是
slow even on a modern computer like what
慢甚至现代计算机像什么
you have the shark machines it takes
你有需要的鲨鱼机
thirty plus clock cycles so anytime the
30个加时钟周期，以便在任何时间
compiler can avoid figure out a trick
编译器可避免想出一个绝招
that does it with shifting and tweaking
与移位和调整做它
things around it will oh so I realized I
它周围的东西会 是如此，我意识到我
should tell you there's a couple ways
应该告诉你有一对夫妇 方式
you can
你 可以
negated number that are handy to know if
否定的数量都得心应手知道
you ever have to do it in your head or
你曾经有这样做在你的头上 或
on paper and the standard way is what's
在纸上的标准方法是什么
called complement and increment so this
所谓的补充和增量所以这
is how do I go from X to minus X so if I
是如何从 X 到零下X，所以如果我
have a number and I want to negate it
有一些，我想否定它
whether it's currently a negative number
无论是当前负数
or it's a positive number the same trick
或者它是一个正数， 同样的伎俩
works what I'll do is complement it
工作原理是什么，我会做的是它的补充
meaning I'll flip all the bits and then
这意味着我会翻转所有的位，然后
I'll add one to that and do the regular
我将添加一个到做正规
sum and so this is six this is minus six
和，所以这是六点为-6
so if you ever have to do it by hand
所以，如果你曾经有手工做
that's the way to do a compliment in
这是 做一个恭维的 方式
increment and it goes the other way
增加和它走另一 条路
you'll see if I compliment this and I
你会看到，如果我 赞美 这和我
increment it I'll get back to my
增加它， 我会回来给我
previous number so that's the trick that
以前的号码，那就是把戏
it's pretty much only useful when you do
当你做这几乎是唯一 有用的
things on the blackboard or when you
事情在黑板上或当您
have to solve a problem in data web
要解决在数据网络中的问题
so anyway this idea of doing a using up
所以无论如何这个想法用起来做的
shifting to the right to do power of two
向右移动做的两个电源
division is actually that's the whole
师实际上这是整个
justification for arithmetic shifting in
理由算术移位在
the first place which by the way in NC
其中第一个地方在 NC 的 方式
there's no fixed requirement for how
还有如何没有固定的要求
shifting works in C for signed numbers
移作品 下签号码
for unsigned it has to be a logical
无符号它必须是一个逻辑
shift sign numbers the C standard says
转移迹象号C标准说
there's no fixed definition the reality
有没有固定的定义， 现实
is on our machines most machines just
是我们的机器大部分机器 刚
about every machine out there when it's
大约每机器在 那里时，它的
a two's complement number when it's a
两公司时，它的补数
negative where it's assigned number
负在那里的 分配 数量
two's complement and when you do a shift
补，当你做一个移
it will be an arithmetic shift
这将是一个算术移位
so getting back to them summarizing this
所以又 回到 了他们这个总结
integer arithmetic you see that first of
你看到的第一个 整数运算
all whether it's signed your unsigned
所有不管 是签署 您的签名
the addition or multiplication
的加法或乘法
operations are the same whether it's a
操作是一样的它是否是一个
unsigned number or two's complement and
无符号数或补和
it works the negative stuff works out as
它的工作原理负面 的东西出来的作品作为
long as you don't have an overflow and
只要 你 没有溢出和
you can end up with an overflow only one
你也可以通过溢出最终只有一个
type of overflow for unsigned in two
在两个无符号溢出型
types four signed numbers but it's not
类型4 符号数，但它不是
like they just overflow and generate
像他们只是溢出且产生
random numbers there's some of a pattern
随机数 有一些图案
to what result what they are and how
什么导致它们是什么，以及如何
they can be interpreted
他们可以 解释
so we I talked about this a little bit
所以我谈到这一点
last time and gave this example similar
最后一次，给了类似的这个例子
to this but let me go over it a little
这可是让我走 在它一点点
bit more one thing you might think of
你可能会觉得有点一件事
while if it's unsigned and signed stuff
而如果它是无符号和签署的东西
gets so murky and we saw some funny
变得这么黑暗 ，我们看到了一些有趣的
examples last time maybe we should just
例子最后一次也许我们应该
vanished unsigned numbers from the
从消失的无符号数
universe and only allow two's complement
宇宙，只允许补
and that's exactly the rule that was
而这正是 这是规则
adopted for example in Java they said
在Java中采用例如他们说
this is too weird what let's just say
这太诡异了 什么让我们只 说
every number is two's complement the
每一个数字是二进制补码
only trick they did was they put in a
只是他们做的诀窍是他们 把一个
triple right shift means logical shift
三重右移指逻辑移位
this is Java this is not C whereas the
这 是Java中，这不是C，而
double is a arithmetic
双是一个 算术
so because they rise there's a lot of
是因为他们上涨有很多的
cute little times when you want to play
当你要玩可爱的小 倍
tricks with things and you need that
事情的技巧和你需要的
logical rate shift so that's actually
逻辑率移 ，这实际上
one approach or other more modern
一种方法或其他更现代
languages and si are saying it's okay to
语言和 Si 说这没关系
have signed and unsigned but we don't
有符号和无符号，但我们不这样做
want them sort of mysteriously being
希望他们有点神秘地被
cast back and forth in ways that the
投来回的方式，将
programmer might not recognize and so
程序员可能无法识别等
you have to explicitly do a cast
你必须明确地做一个投
rather than implicitly and I think
而不是含蓄，我想
that's the better approach but see as I
这是更好的做法，但看到我
mentioned does this implicit casting and
提到这是否隐式转换 和
so as we saw for last time what happens
所以正如我们所看到的最后一次会发生什么
with this program when you run it to
有了这个程序，当 你运行它
count down through an array do you
通过阵列倒计时你
remember
记得
well as I if it's unsigned what will
还有我，如果是无符号 会出现什么
happen with this test it always succeed
这个测试总是成功发生
so the thing will be in an infinite loop
这样的事情将是一个无限 循环
actually what will happen is it will try
居然会发生什么是它 会尝试
to access I will go down to 0 and then
访问我 会下降到 0，然后
it will wrap around to become the
它 会环绕 成为
largest possible unsigned number which
最大可能的无符号数，其
is probably way out of balance and it
可能是出路的平衡;
will give a memory error
会给出一个内存错误
but it won't do what's supposed to be
但它不会做什么的应该是
and as I mentioned before these things
正如我这些事情之前提到的
there's a lot of sneaky ways this
有很多不方便的方面，这
problem can show up in ways you might
可问题的方式显示出来你可能
never think of so for example the
从来没有想到这样的例子中，
operators sizeof is defined to say how
运营商的sizeof定义说 有
big a particular datatype is it's a very
大一个特定的 数据类型 是它是一个非常
useful operator but it's its return
有用的运营商，但它是它的回归
value is a what's called a size
值是 一个什么叫做大小
underscore T which is defined to be a
强调其定义 是 T
long unsigned number and so if we just
长无符号数，因此，如果我们只是
throw in a constant like this then this
在这样的不断抛出那么 这
subtraction we have a sign is now int
减法，我们有一个迹象 是现在诠释
but sizeof is unsigned and so it will
但的sizeof是无符号的，所以它会
cast that to be unsigned implicitly and
强制转换为无符号的含蓄 和
when you compare it to 0 you'll have the
当你把它比作0您将有
same problem as before so just to show
同样的问题，因为以前那么只是为了 显示
you that these things can speak in in
你 认为 这些 东西可以说在
very tricky ways so one way to do that
非常棘手的方式，使一个这样做的方式
then is just don't use unsigned like and
然后只是不要使用无符号 等，
make sure if this is a a possible
要确保，如果这是可能的AA
unsigned number you cast it to signed
无符号数，你 将 其转换 为签署
you make sure this is recognized signed
你要确保这是公认签署
but there's another way that actually at
但还有另一种方式，实际上是在
least there's a fellow over in the
至少有 在 的一个老乡 在
software engineering Institute named
软件工程 学会评选
Robert Secord who has written the books
罗伯特·塞科德谁 写书
that are sooner considered the the gold
被 认为越早的 黄金
standard for how to write secure code he
标准如何编写安全的代码，他
works for this organization called the
适用于这个组织叫
computer emergency response team which
计算机应急响应团队，
is out there tracking down bad things
就在那里跟踪坏事
going on in computer security and one of
在计算机 安全 和一个 事
the things he and others have done is to
他和其他人做的事情是
try and come up with standards so that
试着拿出标准，使
people who write programs will you know
谁写程序的人会知道
avoid some of the pitfalls that make
避免一些让陷阱
their programs vulnerable to the
他们的节目易受
security of laws to attack and so his
法律 安全 攻击等他
recommended technique is when I first
推荐的技术是，当 我第一
saw this it was so counterintuitive to
看到这个它是如此有悖常理 来
me it it hardly made sense right so you
我 来说它几乎是有道理的权利，所以 你
start and again this is all unsigned
开始， 这同样是所有未经签名
arithmetic so I'm starting to count down
算术所以我开始倒计时
and my test is when I is less than count
我测试的时候我不到计数
so here's the thing I started off
所以这里是我开始的东西
smaller than count and it's only being
小于计数，它只是为
decremented so when would this test ever
递减所以当将这个测试过
fail hmm when it overflows when it wraps
失败嗯，当它溢出时，它会返回
around right when I goes from zero and
围绕权 当 我从 零和
counts down to what would now be you max
计数下降到 现在什么是你最大
this test will fail which is exactly
这 会导致 测试 失败而这正是
when you want it to stop and his
当你想让 它停下来 了
observation is and see with signed
观察是看有符号
numbers there's no guarantee on what
数字有 上 没有保证 什么
happens with overflowing as I said most
与我说，大部分发生溢出
people just assume it's going to be
人们只是认为这将是
two's complement but if you really want
补，但是如果你真的想
to be careful you shouldn't assume
要小心， 你不应该假设
anything outside of the C standard and
C标准的 以外的任何与
if you're trying to write secure code
如果你想编写安全的代码
it's probably a good idea to be cautious
它可能是一个好主意，要谨慎
be conservative on the other hand the C
是 另一方面的C保守
standard guarantees it that unsigned
标准保证了它是无符号
arithmetic will be modular arithmetic so
算术将模运算等等
it guarantees that if you subtract one
它保证，如果你减去一个
from zero you'll get the largest number
从 零，你会得到最多
that could be represented so it will be
这 可以 表示所以这将是
okay and in fact he recommends instead
好吧 ，事实上他建议，而不是
of using unsigned which is on our
使用无符号这是对我们的
machines just a 32-bit value that you
机只是一个32位的值，可以
call it a size T which is a 64-bit value
称之为码T这是 一个64位 的值
and so and write your code the way that
所以，写代码的方式，
I showed you so I've actually started
我给你，所以我实际上已经 开始
doing this and once you kind of get used
这样 ，一旦你样的习惯
to it it's an OK way to write code but
它 是写代码的OK的方式 ，但
it's very
这是很
strange looking in this way one thing
奇怪的看着这样一件事
I'll point out is what would happen if
我要指出的是会发生什么，如果
if count were a signed number and int
如果数是有符号数 和INT
and it were you were and it was less
它是你，这 是少
than zero what would happen here so I
大于零的有什么 会发生在这里 等我
less than count what would happen right
不到数会 发生 什么样 的权利
and so it become a very large positive
因此它成为一个非常 大的正
number and this test would almost
数量和本次测试 将几乎
certainly succeed so you have the same
一定会成功，所以你有相同的
this code doesn't avoid the pitfall it
这个代码不避陷阱它
just shifts it to saying you better make
只是把它转移到说你最好使
sure you don't you know test for this
确保你不知道这个测试
case beforehand before you get into it
如果你进入它之前事先
so I think part of it is the observation
所以我觉得它的一部分 是观察
that man if you want to be careful and
那个男人，如果你要小心和
write code that that is guaranteed
编写代码， 这是保证
correct no matter what implementation
正确的不管是什么实现
goes on as long as it's within the CIE
只要它是 CIE 内继续
standard it's pretty tricky business to
标准这是相当棘手的业务
question up there yes
怀疑那里是
which is unfortunate right so yes that's
这是不幸的权 所以是这
exactly the rule that it's implicitly
正是它的隐含规则
silently the C compiler doesn't give any
默默的C编译器不给任何
warnings you'll never know it cast it's
警告你永远不知道它转换 它的
unsigned and as these examples show when
无符号和这些 例子表明，当
you stare at that code and you think
你盯着代码，你认为
about it it's really easy to have bugs
了解 它真的很容易 有错误
that you just you can look at it a
您刚才你可以看看它
thousand times and not realize that it's
一千次，没有意识到 它的
a bug it's a very and there's examples
错误这是一个非常并且有实例
these examples in the book of security
书中安全的这些例子
flaws in sort of very important library
在排序非常重要的库缺陷
software due to this problem exactly
软件 由于这个问题正是
so part of the reason we teach in the
所以我们在教学的部分原因
course is just so you appreciate that
当然是只是让你明白，
this is a quirk in this and see that
这是 这 一个怪癖 ，看到
again 99% of the time you'll never even
再次 的99％的时间你 甚至 永远 都
it won't bother you at all but there
它不会打扰你的所有，但有
will be some oddball cases that you can
会有一些古怪的情况下，你可以
get in trouble with so the other place
惹上麻烦 这么其它地方
that you'll find unsigned arithmetic
你会 发现无符号运算
unsigned representation useful is first
有用的无符号表示是第一
of all when you're doing modular
当你做模块化的所有
arithmetic which is for example the way
算术其例如 路
most encryption algorithms work or when
大多数加密算法的工作或当
you're using the bits not to represent
您正在使用的比特不代表
numbers but to represent sets the way I
数字，但表示台的路上我
described it before then you don't want
描述它之前， 你不希望
it it's easiest to just think of that as
它是最容易 只是觉得， 作为
unsigned numbers okay so the final thing
无符号数好了 ，所以最后 的事情
to talk about today is some of the
今天 要谈 的 是一些
low-level representations of numbers
数字的低级别交涉
within memory and the main point is when
存储器内，并且主要的一点是当
you are running a program on a computer
您在计算机上 运行的程序
from the programming perspective either
从编程的角度 无论是
even as an assembly level programmer not
甚至作为一个组件水平程序员不
just as a C programmer in your mind the
就像在你的心中一个C程序员
memory is just this big array of bytes
内存字节的只是这个大阵
that's numbered from 0 up to some
这是一个从0开始编号高达一些
maximum number so for example in the
最大数量，以便例如在
machines we're using the 64-bit machines
我们使用64位机器的机器
an address is represented in 64 bits but
的地址被以64个比特表示，但
in fact the maximum address you're
其实最大地址你
allowed to use in current machines is a
不允许在当前机器使用 一个
47 bits and to the forty-seventh is
47位和到 第四十七是
still a pretty big number so that's more
仍然是一个相当 大 的 数量， 以便 更
memory than anyone's able to buy right
内存比任何人的能 买权
now anyhow and so it's a reasonable
现在无论如何，所以它是一个合理的
restriction but the point is that
限制，但问题是，
logically your program thinks that it
逻辑程序认为它
has a array of
具有的阵列
at many bites let's try and figure out
在许多叮咬 ，让我们试着找出
how big to xlvii is anyone know it off
任何人有多大，以四十七 知道它关闭
the top of their head so there's a trick
他们的头顶 ， 所以有窍门
if you want to get an approximate idea
如果你想获得一个大致的想法
which is to say that 2 to the 10th which
这是 说，2 至10日 这
is 110 24 is approximately equal to 10
是110 24约等于 10
to the third you say oh well that's
第三 ，你说哦 那
really helpful what it means is that 10
真正有用的 是什么意思的是，10
bits worth of number is about the same
位数的身价是差不多的
as three decimal digits
作为 三个十进制数字
all right so for example 2 to the 20th
没事因此，例如2到20
is around 10 to the 6 2 to the 30th it's
大约是10〜6 2到它的第30
around 10 to the 9th to the 40th around
约10至9日到周围40
10 to the 12th and so that would tell
10至12日 ，因此这会告诉
you that 2 to the 48-47 is around 128
你说2到48-47 大约是 128
times 10 to the 12th which is 128
乘以10， 其是128第十二
terabyte right Tara 10 to the 12 so if
TB的正确的塔拉 10到12，所以如果
you just want to say you know get a
你只想说你也知道得到
quick figure 4 and of course these are
快图4，当然这些都是
approximations but if you just want to
近似的，但如果你只是想
get a quick handle on how big a number
得到了多大的次数迅速把手
you know what range of values can I
你知道什么值范围 可我
represent with so many bits of it this
与它这个很多位代表
is a really easy trick to do that so the
是 一个非常简单的 把戏 做到这一点，因此
point is a 128 terabytes
点是128兆兆字节
is a lot you can buy disk drives a
是很多，你可以买到磁盘驱动器
couple of disk drives will do that for
夫妇磁盘驱动器会替
you but you couldn't buy enough DRAM on
你，但你不能买上没有足够的DRAM
a normal budget to get that kind of
正常预算得到的那种
memory so that's the current range of
内存中，这样的电流 范围
values but logically when you run a
值，但在逻辑上，当您运行
program it thinks that it has that
程序它认为它有
possible range now it
现在可能范围之
doesn't really and in fact what happens
并不是真的，事实上发生了什么
is that the operating system only allows
是操作系统只允许
certain regions within that memory to be
该存储器内的某些区域是
referenced and other regions if you try
引用等地区，如果你尝试
to access them it will create a it will
访问这些它会创建一个它会
signal an error what they call a
发出错误信号人们常说的
segmentation fault but logically at
分段错误，但 在逻辑
least it's as if you have this big array
至少这是因为，如果你有这个大阵
of bytes now in reality and we'll go
现在的字节在现实中 ，我们会去
into this when we talk about how the
到这个时候，我们谈论 的是如何
memory system is works in virtual memory
存储系统虚拟内存的作品
there's this very complex combination of
有这种非常复杂的组合
hardware and software that gives the
硬件和 软件， 使该
program this image of a very large what
节目的一个非常大的这一形象是什么
you call flap space just a big array of
你叫襟翼空间只是一个大阵列
bytes when in reality it's shuffling
而实际上它的洗牌字节
between different regions of your memory
你的内存的 不同区域之间
and even between your memory and your
甚至你的记忆和你之间
disk drive on your computer to make it
在您的 计算机 上的磁盘驱动器 ，使它
implement this particular idea that you
实现这个特别的想法，你
have this big array of bytes and that's
有个字节的这个大阵，这就是
all handled as I said by the operating
所有处理正如我所说的 操作
system by the computer hardware and it's
系统 由计算机硬件 ，它的
largely invisible even to the machine
主要是无形 甚至到 机器
level programmer even people writing
级程序员甚至还有人写
assembly code you'll often hear the term
汇编代码，你会经常听到这个词
word size and it can get very confusing
字的大小，它可以变得 非常混乱
confusing nowadays because there's no
如今混乱的，因为没有
really fixed idea of what a word size is
的字长是真正固定观念
but roughly speaking the word size
但大致来说字长
should be whatever the largest number is
应该是无论数量最多
that or the range that sort of signifies
表示的该或范围那样
how big a pointer is in this language or
有多大的指针是在此语言或
Hardware wise the largest sort of chunk
明智五金最大的 那种大块的
of hardware for which there's standard
硬件针对有标准
support for storing it for arithmetic
用于存放算术支持
operations and so forth so when we say
操作等等，所以当我们说
it's a 64-bit machine what we mean is
这是一个64位的 机器我们的意思是
that it it regular and routinely
它它经常和定期
manipulate 64-bit values err on
操纵 64位值宁可
arithmetic operations and also it has a
算术运算并且还具有
pointers or the values of addresses are
指针或地址的值是
64 bits
64 位
even if for right now only 47 of those
即使现在 只有 47
bits are usable it's still considered a
位是可用的，它仍然 被认为是
64-bit machine one thing that strange is
64位计算机一件事情 ，奇怪的是，
in one of the features of of machines
在机器的的特征之一
such as we have huh is that if I compile
比如我们吧，如果我编译
a program using a GCC the standard
使用GCC 标准的程序
compiler I can specify either I want it
编译器我可以指定 我想它
to be 64 bit code or 32-bit code as a
为64位的代码或32位代码 作为
flag and it will actually generate two
标志，它实际上会生成两个
different kinds of object code as a
不同种类 的对象代码作为
result and we'll talk in a look about
结果，我们将在一起来看看有关谈话
these later but for right now the point
这些后来但对现在的点
is the hardware itself doesn't
是硬件本身不
necessarily define what the word size is
一定规定字长是 什么
it's a combination of the hardware and
它是整合了硬件和
the compiler that determines what is the
决定什么 是编译器
word size being used in this particular
字的大小 在此 特定 使用
program and that code can be run on the
程序和代码可以 在运行
point is the 64 bit machine such as we
点是64比特机器， 如我们
have and most machines are nowadays can
有大部分机器都可以时下
insert of a backward compatibility style
插入的向后兼容性风格
also execute 32-bit code and as we also
还 执行32位代码，并为我们也
saw one of the other features is even
看到的其他特征之一，即使是
though it's a 64 bit word size the data
虽然这是一个64位字长的数据
type int without any other qualifiers to
没有任何其它限定符来int类型
it is just 32 bits so the sort of this
它仅仅是32位 ，因此排序的这
mixture of how big things are so when
到底有多大的事情都那么当混合
people just say word or word size and
人们只是说的词或字的大小 和
let's say give a precise definition
假设给出一个确切的定义
that's not a very meaningful term and
这不是一个非常有意义的期限和
we'll sort of throw it around when we
我们有点把它周围的时候，我们
mean sort of a generic chunk of bits
意味着排序位的通用块的
without trying to assume that it has a
不尝试假设它有一个
particular number of bits to it
位 到它 的特定数
yes so one of the things is if we ever
是这样的事情之一是，如果我们曾经
get to 64-bit words it will be 16
得到64位的话 这将是16
petabytes 18 petabytes opinion how you
高数量18个PB的意见 如何
define when you those numbers get big
当这些数字变大定义
the error due to this approximation gets
误差由于这种近似变
more significant but something times 10
更显著但一些10倍
to the 15th bytes but right now we can
到15字节，但现在我们可以
only get to 128 times 10 to the 12 so
只得到128次，每次10到 12这样
anyway it's the idea that the memory
反正它的想法， 记忆
itself is a series of bytes but we can
本身就是一系列的字节数，但我们可以
group those into blocks of words of
基团的那些成的字块
different word sizes and the way we do
不同的字长，我们做的方式
that is usually by assuming that the the
通常是通过假定 的
address of the word is the lowest valued
字的地址是最低值
address in it and we also will generally
解决它，我们通常还会
try to align these so that for example a
尝试协调这使得例如一个
32-bit word would be a line so its first
32位字将是一个行，以便 它的第一
byte its lowest byte has all zeros in
字节的最低字节在所有零
the frick stuff
弗里克东西
in the first five bit positions right
在前五位位置向右
now 32 4 I'm sorry the lowest two bytes
现年32 4 对不起最低的两个字节
right so as this example shows their
右从而这个例子说明了其
address is 0 4 8 and 12 they should have
地址是0 4 8和12，他们应该有
really written this in hex and said it's
真的写了这个十六进制，并说这是
C I guess these are all in decimal
C I想这些都是十进制
anyhow so yeah these are decimal numbers
无论如何所以是这些都是十进制数
so 0 4 8 12 so you see these are in
所以0 4 8 12 所以你看这些都是
multiples of 4 of bit boundaries and
的比特边界的4的倍数和
similarly the 64-bit words are in
类似地，64位的字是在
multiples of 8 and those are known as
8的倍数和那些被称为
aligned words and will generally will
对齐的字，并且一般 会
see that the compiler works pretty hard
见编译器工作很辛苦
to keep things aligned because the
让事情，因为对齐
hardware runs more efficiently that way
硬件更有效地运行， 这样
but the main point is that we can just
但主要的一点是 ， 我们可以只
take as many bytes as we want and
因为我们希望采取尽可能多的字节，
collect them together and call it a word
收集在一起，并把它称为一个字
for whatever word size we need and as we
不管是什么字的大小，我们需要和我们
think we saw a variant of this table
认为我们看到这个表的一个变种
before but this is the machines we'll be
之前，但 这样 的机器，我们会
working on that the standard int is
工作的标准int是
still only 32 bits but if we qualify
仍然只有32 位 ，但如果我们晋级
something as being wrong then it will be
一些为错误的，那么这将是
64 bits and will tend to do that there's
64位， 往往会做到这一点有
two different floating-point
两个不同的浮点
representations that we'll talk about
我们将谈论交涉
and then the main feature of a 64 bit
然后一个64 位 的主要特征
machine is it has an 8 byte or 64 bit
机是它有一个8字节或64位
pointer as compared to 32 now there's
指针相比，32现在有
one other kind of detail that says ok so
一个其他类型的细节， 说好了，所以
if a word has multiple bytes in it what
如果一个单词中有多个字节什么
order should those bytes be should it be
为了应这些字节是 它 应该 是
the and these two basic ways this could
在这两个 基本方面，这可能
go one is that you put the bytes in
去一个就是你把 字节
what's known as little endian order
什么是被称为小尾数顺序
meaning that the first byte in the word
这意味着 在单词 的 第一个字节
is the least significant byte and then
是最显著字节，然后
the next and then the next and the final
接下来再 下 ，最终
byte in the word is the most significant
在字字节是最显著
or you can flip that around and those
或者你可以翻转周围那些
are called little-endian and big-endian
被称为小端和大端
is the
是个
the sort of terms for that which comes
排序条件的那所附带
from a English book called Gulliver's
从英语书叫格列佛
Travels which didn't anticipate
游记里面也没有预料
computers at all but it's an interesting
在所有的计算机，但它是一个有趣的
story of how that comes about
如何自带约故事
so in out there in the world you'll find
所以在外面的世界，你会发现
both types of machines big Indian and
这两种类型的 机器 大的印度和
little Indian machines it turns out that
事实证明，小印度的机器，
increasingly it's getting hard to find
越来越它越来越难找到
big Indian machines so little indeed all
印度大型机器那么一点实际上所有
of x86 is little Indian and it turns out
86是小印度和原来
ARM processors like what you have in
ARM处理器一样，你有什么
almost every cell phone here is an ARM
这里几乎每个手机是ARM
processor and the hardware and those can
处理器和硬件和那些罐
actually be configured to run either way
实际上被配置为运行无论哪种方式
big-endian or little-endian but when
大端或小端，但是当
you're running it on any of the standard
你在任何 标准的运行它
operating systems that run on ARM
上ARM上运行的操作系统
processors then it's running little
处理器则它的运行 小
Indian so there used to be a brand
印度因此曾经有 一个品牌
called Sun Microsystems and they were
所谓Sun Microsystems和他们
fairly common on campus and then back in
在校园里相当普遍的，然后再 在
the Macintosh before they were x86
在Macintosh他们前86
processors they ran one called the
处理器他们跑了一个叫
PowerPC and that was a big engine
PowerPC的， 这是一个大引擎
machine but those are long in the
机器，但这些都是长在
distant past the internet about the only
遥远的过去有关的唯一互联网
place out there when you send packets
放置在那里，当你发送的数据包
over the internet you want to send in
在 互联网 上 ，你 要发送 的
32-bit words they're actually sent in
他们实际上是在发送 32位 字
big endian order and so at the network
大端秩序等在网络
interface you have to translate between
接口就得之间进行转换
those two so again just to illustrate
这两个如此反复 只是 为了说明
what I mean by this is think of a byte
我的意思是，这是一个字节的思考
value for byte value like this and
像这样和字节值值
remember that the way we write numbers
请记住，在路上，我们写号
is we put the most significant to the
是我们把最显著的
left and the least significant to the
左边和最不显著
right
对
and so now with a big-endian inserted
所以现在有一个 大端 插入
the intuitive one from that perspective
从这一角度直观一个
in that the bike if you write the words
在自行车 ，如果你写的字
in memory from the smallest address up
从最小地址内存
to the highest the big endian will sort
以最高的大端将整理
of map to what you see whereas the
映射到你所看到的 ， 而
little endian will look confusing that
小尾数看起来很奇怪的是
you say 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 because 6 7 is
你说0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 6因为7是
actually the least significant byte here
实际上至少显著 这里 字节
and so that comes first in little-endian
所以在首先出现在小尾数
order and and so the it used to be
顺序和与如此使用的它是
people would get in passionate arguments
人们会得到热情的论据
about this that sort of in the distant
这个那种 在遥远
past but and people saying you know and
过去，但人们 说你知道和
the main feature in some sort of
在 某种主要 特征
argument of big indian nuts is this
印度 大型 坚果 的说法是这样的
feature here that when you look at it
此功能 ，当 你看它
it's easier to write down but computers
它更容易写下来，但电脑
don't really care they're happy either
真的不关心他们要么很高兴
way and so they just want one convention
方式 ，所以他们只是 想要一个约定
or another and like I said some
或另一就像我说的一些
hardware's can actually be a by a sort
硬件的可以通过一种实际上是一个
of flag to flip it from being big endian
标志以被大端翻转
to little Indian but the reality is most
到小印度， 但 现实的情况是 最
of machines one counter you'll encounter
机器一个计数器 ， 你会遇到
a little endian machine stoudek but just
小端机stoudek只是
to give you an example here's some
在这里举一个例子是一些
results that I got from actual machines
结果我从实际 的机器 了
there used to be some machines around so
曾经有一些机器 使 周围
back in the old days I could run this I
早在过去，我可以运行这个我
don't even know where to get a big
甚至不知道从哪里 得到大
endian machine anymore so these are sort
endian机器了，所以这些都是排序
of legacy result but you'll see that the
传统的结果 ，但你会看到，
main feature is between a little Indian
主要特点是小印度之间
and a big endian machine when you have
和大端机器 ，当你 有
an integer the bikes get flipped around
整数自行车出行翻转
so that the re significant byte comes
使再 显著 字节来
first in a little endian machine and
首先在小端机
last in a big endian machine and that's
最后在大端机器，这就是
true with negative numbers as well that
负数也是如此说
you'll get the sign bits first in a big
你会在一个大先拿到符号位
endian machine a long
endian机器长时间
you'll see that the only difference
你会看到， 唯一 的 区别
between a 32-bit machine the 64-bit
32位 机器64位 之间
machine is you have more zeros or more
机器是你有更多的零以上
ones depending whether it's a positive
那些视 它是否是一个积极的
or negative number and again the Sun and
或负数 ，再次 太阳和
if I had access to a 64-bit machine Sun
如果我有访问64位机 太阳
is now manufactured by a company called
现在由一家名为制造
Oracle so in principle I could go get
甲骨文所以在原则上我可以去喝
one of these machines and run this
这些机器中的一个并运行此
experiment but it's really not a very
实验，但它真的不是一个 很
interesting experiment so I won't bother
有趣的实验，所以我不会打扰
so in principle I could try it on a
所以在原则上，我可以尝试 在一个
64-bit Oracle machine and show you
64位Oracle机，并且告诉你
something different so one thing that
不同的东西这样一两件事，
kind of a useful tool the book goes
一种有用的 工具书去
through some examples of this is a
通过这样一些实例中是一个
little program that will take a series
小程序， 将采取 一系列
of bytes starting at some position start
开始 在 一些位置 开始 的字节
and do it for however many bytes you
也为了然而，许多字节您
request and just print out in hex format
要求，只是打印出十六进制格式
the two hex digits that represent that
两个十六进制数字代表的是
bite valve and here this term pointer
咬阀，在这里这个词指针
I'm using an unsigned care as a pointer
我使用的是无符号的关怀作为一个指针
type a sort of generic pointer type
键入一种通用的指针类型
and so again if I run this on a x86
所以再次，如果我在86运行此
machine oh oh and I'm also by the way
机哦，哦，我也顺便说一下
printing out the actual address that
打印出的实际地址
this character is stored in too and so
这个字符存储 在太 等
you'll see that there is these addresses
你会看到有这些地址
with a lot of 7f of what that means is
有很多的手段是什么1408米
it's in the upper end of this 47 bit
它是这个 47位 的上端
address space if you work it through
如果你的工作，通过地址空间
there's seven is three ones and then
有七个是三一，然后
there's enough hex digits here to
这里有足够的十六进制数字来
correspond to so there's 11 hex digits
对应所以有11个十六进制数字
beyond the seven and you'll see that
超越七，你会看到，
these addresses are at successive bytes
这些地址是在连续的字节
BC B DB EB F and the values are 63 B 0 0
BC乙DB EB F和值是63 乙0 0
0 0 this is the least significant byte
0 0 这是最显著字节
and these are the successive byte and a
而这些都是连续字节和一个
similar I can I can use this to examine
类似的，我可以，我可以用它来检查
pointers of various sorts and I can
不同的种类 可以和我 的指针
examine different values and just get
考察不同的价值观和刚刚获得
their low-level byte representations and
其低级别的字节表示和
so I did this back when I could get to a
所以我做了这个回来时，我能 得到一个
Sun machine it had one way of
孙机它有一种方式
representing a pointer and the main
代表一个指针和主
point is even across machines whether
点甚至是跨机器是否
it's a byte ordering or whatever you'll
这是一个字节顺序或任何你会
get different values for pointers
获得指针不同的值
there's no guarantee that when you load
有没有保证， 当你 加载
them a computer program into one machine
这些计算机程序为一体机
and run it that it will use the same
并运行它，它会使用相同的
addresses as that same programming
地址为相同的编程
running on a different machine even if
在不同的机器，即使上运行
actually they're identical hardware and
其实他们是相同的硬件 和
operating system there can be variation
操作系统可以有变化
because pointers aren't you can't
因为指针不是你不行
directly copy a pointer from one machine
直接指针从一台计算机复制
to another on one thing about also is
另一个对一件事也是
regardless of byte ordering the ordering
无论字节的排序顺序
of of characters is the same and so a
的字符是相同的，所以
string in C is always represented by a
在C字符串总是 由 表示
series of bytes where the final byte is
一系列字节，其中最后一个字节是
called null-terminated and the
所谓空值终止和
individual bytes correspond to the
单个字节对应于
character codes for that number and
该数字的字符代码和
these character codes are just sometimes
这些字符代码只是有时
called ASCII format which is a little
所谓的ASCII格式这是一个小
bit old-fashioned by the way there's
位的方式老式的有
more modern character codes too that can
更现代的字符代码 也可以
represent non English alphabets but the
代表非 英文字母 ，但
C standard is still back in the days of
C标准仍然是早在天
only supporting the the ASCII format
只有配套的ASCII格式
question uh-huh yes so this should have
问题 嗯没错 所以这应该有
been well no this is good so I'm casting
一直 没有 好 ，这是很好的 ，所以我铸造
I want to show the for bite-size event
我想显示为一口大小事件
for because this is an int I'm
对于因为这是一个int我
representing the pointer let's see the
代表指针让我们来看看
code we're printing the pointer all this
代码中，我们要打印指针这一切
notation % P is the directive to say
符号％P是说指令
print out a pointer proposed right and %
打印出的指针提出正确的和％
X is the directive to print out a hex
X是打印 出的十六进制 指令
representation so it's printing out both
代表，所以它都打印出来
the address the starting position of
该地址的起始位置
that particular byte and the value of
该特定字节和的值
that byte as two different things does
该字节作为两个不同的 东西 呢
that answer your question
这回答你的问题
returning upper darker yes but remember
返回上层深色可以，但请记住
show bytes is being given a pointer and
显示字节报错一个指针和
a length and so what this is and what
长度还等什么，这是什么
it's saying is starting at that address
它的说法是从该地址开始
print out the next series of bytes for
打印 出下一个 系列的字节
me how many bytes I asked for and in
我我有多少字节的要求和
this case I'm I'm creating a pointer to
这种情况下，我是我创建的指针
this integer but I want to show the the
这个整数，但 我想显示的
bytes in that integer the four bytes
在整数字节的四个字节
that make up that integer and that's why
组成该整数 ，这就是为什么
I'm giving it the number four here
我给 它排名 第四这里
instead of eight is it yes it will be
而不是8 是它是的，它 会
and that's fine because in this code I'm
这很好，因为在此代码我
using the percent P directive to
使用％ 对指令
designate how to print out the pointer
指定如何打印 出指针
and that will print it as many bytes as
以及将打印的字节数
it takes for that particular machine
它需要为特定的机器
that it's running on so percent P is
它的 运行就这么％的 P是
actually a very handy directive if you
实际上是一个非常方便的指令，如果你
have to print addresses like for
要打印像地址
debugging purposes or something because
调试的目的或东西，因为
it will automatically adapt to whatever
它会自动适应任何
machine it's running on question
机器它的问题上运行
well I've defined it to be an unsigned
还有我定义它是一个无符号
care here so type def is a way to
关心这里，所以类型定义是一种方法，
introduce a name for some of data type
对于一些数据类型的引入名字
right and so I've just declared a
右 ，所以我刚刚宣布
pointer quote pointer to refer to an
指针引用指针指到
unsigned care if you did a void star it
无符号的护理如果你没有一个无效加上星
would not be happy with this reference
不会满意这个参考
here right you can't you can't reference
在这里 对 你不能，你 不能引用
a void star is just a way to pass around
空洞明星只是一种 绕过 路
a generic pointer but you can't actually
一个通用的指针，但你不能真正
reference that element so what I'm
引用元素，我还等什么
basically doing is saying this reference
基本上做的是说 这 句话的 引用
is treated like an array you treat my
是像对待你对待一个数组我
series of bytes is an array and print
一系列字节 是一个数组和打印
out each of the bytes in that array and
出每个阵列中的字节和
so here where I'm a is a number and I'm
所以在这里，我是一个是一个数字，我
taking the address of that integer and
采取这一整数的地址，
casting it to be an unsigned care star
铸造它是一个无符号的护理明星
so sort of a generic slightly generic
所以排序的一个通用略微通用
pointer but not quite as generic as void
指针，但并不像一般为void
star and then printing it up
星吧，然后打印出来了
was it good quite easy good questions by
它是由好很容易好的 问题
the way okay so the point being that
路好了，所以点在于
strings are just strings and that's the
字符串仅仅是字符串，这就是
same from one machine to the next okay
从一台机器一样到下一行不行
let's finish up today with some puzzles
我们今天完成了一些困惑
and these have this annoying way of
而这些有这种恼人的方式
showing up on exams so it's worth being
显示出来的考试， 所以它是值得的
able to do these kind of things and
能够做这类事情 和
you'll also notice I cleverly did not
你还会注意到 我巧妙地没
include the answers in the slide
包括在幻灯片的答案
so you can't you can't just peek ahead
所以你不能，你不能只是提前偷看
and figure out what the answers are so
并找出问题的答案是如此
let's just go through them but I
让我们只是通过他们去，但我
actually worked them out to make sure I
实际工作出来，以 确保我
had the entry zone so if X and basically
有入口区 ，所以如果X和基本
these are sort of statements that you
这些类型的语句， 你
want to say these are either always true
要说这些都是要么 总是正确的
and maybe there's some logic behind why
也许还有背后为什么一些逻辑
it's always true or possibly false and
它总是真或假的可能 和
you won't have to give some example that
你会不会 给一些例子
would make that false so let's go
会提出这样的假让我们去
through these as many as we have time
通过这些多达我们有时间
for and see where we get to so if I take
并看到我们去，所以如果我走
X and I double it multiply it by 2 if X
X和我双击它乘以2，如果X
who are negative and my guaranteed that
谁是阴性，我保证
2x will be negative
2X将是 负
no so by the way one general way to find
没有那么顺便说一个普通的方式找到
counter examples is to try team in it's
相反的例子是尝试队在它的
a really good one and that works here
一个很好的一个，并且在这里工作
right if I take team n which is one and
右如果我带的团队n的是一个和
a bunch of zeros I double it like
一串零的我加倍 喜欢
shifting it but left and it will become
移，但 左，它将成为
what zero right is and so again assume
什么0右就是等再次 假设
that X is that any negative number and
X是任何负数和
UX is it's unsigned I'm sorry
UX是它的无符号对不起
two's complement number and UX is what
二进制补码数和用户体验是什么
happens if I cast it to be unsigned so
如果发生我投它 是无符号等等
as u X always you're greater than or
为u 总是X 你比大于或
equal to zero yeah that's slightly more
等于零 ， 是啊，这稍微
obscure if I take X and I mask off seven
晦涩如果我带X和我屏蔽掉 7
you remember is the bit pattern 1 1 1 so
你还记得是位模式1 1 1 所以
as I mask off all but the lowest 3 bits
如我屏蔽掉所有，但最低的 3个比特
and I find that those are all one I'm
我发现，这些 都是一个我
already giving you the answer here and
这里已经给你答案和
then I shift it left by 30 position what
然后我转向它由30位留下什么
can I say about the result
我可以说结果
so I know the ex must finish with 3:1
所以我知道前必须完成 3：1
right and I shift that by 30 and this
正确的，我的转变，由30 这
these will be the only two bits that are
这些将是 唯一 的 两位是
left after the shifting and they will be
在换档之后的左和他们将
in the most significant position so what
最显著位置等什么
can I say about that number is negative
我可以说 这个数字为负
so this is a true statement rather
所以这是一个真正的语句，而
obscure but it is true is UX greater
晦涩，但它是真实的 UX 更大
than minus one
比减 一
it's almost true right the one counter
这几乎是真正的权利 的一个 计数器
example would be what the zoo well
例如会是怎样的动物园 以及
actually no you're right there's a lot
其实也没什么，你是对的还有很多
of examples it's hardly ever true it's
的例子是几乎没有真正的是
almost always false
几乎都是假的
I was wrong the only thing that would
我错了的事情中唯一会
make it true would be XI it's never true
它是真的会是十一它从来没有真正的
okay so it's never true okay if X is
好了，这是从来没有真正的好 ，如果X是
greater than Y is minus X less than
大于Y是负X小于
minus y
减Y
No so by the way one thing we didn't
没有这样的方式一件事 我们没有
really cover is what is the negative of
真正涵盖什么是负的
tea men and to see that we can use our
茶男人看到，我们可以用 我们的
complement income instrument trick so
补收益 工具 欺骗等等
when you compliment an increment T min
当你赞美 一个增量T最小
you get T min and that's why it's such a
你T最小，这就是为什么它是这样一个
great counter example so in particular
伟大的反例所以特别
if Y is T min and X is something else
如果Y是t最小和X是别的东西
then that left-hand part will be true
那么左侧部分 为真
but the right-hand part will not be true
但右侧部分不会是真的
okay x times X greater than or equal to
行x倍X大于或等于
zero we've seen examples of that being
零个，我们已经看到 了 存在 的例子
false
假
if X is it is just kind of silly if X is
如果X是它只是有种傻 如果X是
greater than zero and Y is greater than
大于 零且Y 大于
zero is X plus y greater than zero no if
零为X加上Y大于零，如果没有
X is greater than or equal to zero is
X是大于或 等于零的
minus X less than or equal to zero
减去X 小于或等于零
gotcha
疑难杂症
you're right it's true right because
你是对的这是真的正确的，因为
that but let's take it counterpart if X
这一点，但我们把 它 对口如果X
is less than or equal to zero is minus x
小于 或等于零是减去 x
squared equals zero team n right so
平方 等于零 队n右 等等
right the point being that the largest
右边的点是，最大的
any positive number can be represented
任何正数可以表示
as negative but there's one negative
为阴性，但有一个负
number that can't be represented as
不能被表示为 编号
positive and so that asymmetry is why
积极使不对称是为什么
you get different answers to these if I
你如果我不同的答案，这些
take X and I look at minus X and I shift
拍X 我期待在零下X和我转移
them to the right by 31 am I going to
他们由31右 我该怎么
get all ones this is a really weird
让所有 的人，这是一个非常奇怪的
statement
声明
so it actually kind of works right if I
因此它实际上样的作品的权利，如果我
take all zeros
采取一切为零
and I subtract one I'll get minus one
我减去一个我会减一
and I or them that works so what's wrong
我还是他们的作品有啥错
with this what's that oh but if I shift
本那是什么 哦，但如果我转向
it to the right 31 places that's going
它正确 地31这是怎么回事
to shift arithmetic aliy what's that oh
转移算术aliy那是什么啊
I see oh I'm sorry
我看看哦对不起
I already jumped ahead to a different
我已经跳到了一个不同的
puzzle X and minus X and I so you're
拼图X和X负和我 所以你
right actually
其实权
if the two numbers is zero and I or
如果这两个数字是 零，我还是
those I get zero but you'll figure out
那些我得到零，但你会找出
you'll notice if it's anything non zero
如果它是任何非零你会发现
actually this will be true and that's an
实际上这将是真实的 ，并且是一个
interesting feature so there's a couple
有趣的功能，所以有一对夫妇
other puzzles and I'll I'll let you
其他的拼图，我会我会告诉你
solve those on your own we're all set
解决这些你自己，我们都是集
for today
今天